<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radiative Transfer on Zero Radiance</title>
    <link>https://zero-radiance.github.io/tags/radiative-transfer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radiative Transfer on Zero Radiance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zero-radiance.github.io/tags/radiative-transfer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From Particle to Volume Scattering</title>
      <link>https://zero-radiance.github.io/post/particle-volume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zero-radiance.github.io/post/particle-volume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://zero-radiance.github.io/post/analytic-media/&#34;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt; covered the basics of the volume scattering process. It models the macroscopic interaction of light and matter, with the latter represented as a distribution of &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/qj.49708436025&#34;&gt;small particles&lt;/a&gt;. Fundamentally, the volume scattering process arises from the microscopic interaction of light with individual atoms, and is typically described using &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1364/JOSAA.35.000163&#34;&gt;Maxwell&#39;s electromagnetic theory&lt;/a&gt;. It is the domain of optics, and, in my experience, the connection with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radiative_transfer#The_equation_of_radiative_transfer&#34;&gt;radiative transfer equation&lt;/a&gt; is neither apparent nor easy to find. The purpose of this blog post is to familiarize the reader with domain-specific terms and ease the adoption of formulas found in the optics literature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling Analytic Participating Media</title>
      <link>https://zero-radiance.github.io/post/analytic-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zero-radiance.github.io/post/analytic-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rendering of participating media is an important aspect of every modern renderer. When I say participating media, I am not just talking about fog, fire, and smoke. All matter is composed of &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.lumenlearning.com/boundless-chemistry/chapter/the-structure-of-the-atom/&#34;&gt;atoms&lt;/a&gt;, which can be sparsely (e.g. in a gas) or densely (e.g. in a solid) distributed in space. Whether we consider the particle or the wave nature of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light&#34;&gt;light&lt;/a&gt;, it penetrates all matter (even &lt;a href=&#34;http://webhome.phy.duke.edu/~qelectron/group/group_reading_Born_and_Wolf.pdf&#34;&gt;metals&lt;/a&gt;) to a certain degree and interacts with its atoms along the way. The nature and the degree of &amp;quot;participation&amp;quot; depend on the material in question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>